Yuriy Shapkin

Application Engineer, full stack ECMAScript development.

15+ years of software engineering and user interface experience, with strong analytical skills and a range of computer expertise.

Solution architect for the management systems, online learning, social networks.

github: <u>yurks</u> linkedin: <u>yurks</u> tg: <u>@yurks</u>

mailto: yurkins@gmail.com

Technical kills

- ECMAScript (JavaScript), TypeScript, PHP
- Vue.js/Quasar/Vuetify, Svelte, Angular, React, Knockout, jQuery
- Nuxt.js, Webpack, Grunt, Gulp, Rollup
- Node.js, Express, Socket.io, JWT
- MongoDB, Elasticsearch, MySQL
- HTML, XML/XLT, CSS, LESS, SASS, Stylus
- Heroku, AWS Lambda, Apache, Tomcat
- Git, Docker/Compose, Gerrit, GitHub, NPM, SVN
- Jira, TargetProcess, Slack
- Photoshop, Illustrator, Flash

Experience

degree.me (2019-2021, AcademixDirect)

Application to find and contact the education institution using locations, programs and comparing college details. Modern waysto attract, engage and educate potential students by helping them connect their goals to the right educational path.

Role: Full Stack Engineer

Responsibilities: API and application architecture; integration with third-party services; user interface development; server-side coding

Team: 2 developers

Technologies: Vue.js, Quasar, SASS, Nuxt.js, Webpack, Node.js, Sails.js, JWT,

Elasticsearch, Docker/Compose

aceagents.io (2020, AcademixDirect)

Administration system of Al-powered virtual agents.

Role: Front End Engineer

Responsibilities: UI/UX development

Team: 1 developer

Technologies: Vue.js, Vue CLI, Vuetify, SASS, JWT

degree.me/bot (2018, AcademixDirect)

PSER chatbot for Facebook. **Role**: Back End Engineer

Responsibilities: integration with third-party services; server-side coding

Team: 1 developers

Technologies: Node.js, Facebook API, Gulp

axd.co (2013-2017, AcademixDirect)

Internal management system. **Role**: Front End Engineer

Responsibilities: API and application architecture; UI/UX development

Team: 7 developers

Technologies: AngularJS, LESS, Webpack

axdapi.com (2011-2015, AcademixDirect)

Cross-device modular plugin for building UI forms by JSON-schema and communicating with API.

Role: JavaScript Developer, Team Lead

Responsibilities: plugin architecture and development; product documentation

Team: 3 developer

Technologies: JavaScript, JSONP, Webpack

plus3network.com (2010, Plus3Network)

Mobile, GPS-enhanced social network that connects people with corporate sponsors and worthwhile causes on a lasting journey of personal fitness and charitable giving.

Role: Web Developer

Responsibilities: Developing user interface, page markup and styling

Team: 5 developers

Technologies: JavaScript, Ajax, jQuery, HTML, CSS, Phyton. MySQL, PostgreSQL

mtv.ua (2009, MTV Media Network)

Online network for Ukrainian MTV media.

Role: Web Developer

Responsibilities: Developing user interface, page markup, server-side coding.

Team: 3 developers

Technologies: JavaScript, jQuery, HTML, CSS, PHP, Drupal, Apache

projectsolaris.eu (2008, Polish Academy of Sciences)

Online representation of Polish space project.

Role: Web Developer

Responsibilities: Developing user interface, page markup, server-side coding.

Team: 2 developer

Technologies: JavaScript, jQuery, HTML, CSS, PHP, Apache.

elearning-pto.gov.ua (2002-2008, Ministry of Education and Science of Ukraine)

E-learning system with lesson management, distance teacher and powerful testing modules for Ukrainian schools and colleges.

Role: Web Developer, UX Designer

Responsibilities: Developing user interface, page markup and styling

Team: 4 developers

Technologies: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Java, XML, Tomcat

Education

Master's degree in Electronics Engineering, Kharkiv National University of Radio Electronics (1998-2003).

Graduate work: Distance Education system, winner of year graduate contest. Two scientific works published.

Side projects

- Online stores like <u>azature.com</u>, <u>sigma.ua</u>, event schedulers like <u>yogahouse.kharkov.ua</u>, personal websites like <u>andrewbrooke.com</u>
- Electronic Devices: Micro-controller programming, PCB design.
- Network administration: Domain controller, Network topology, TCP/IP, Cisco IOS, Ericsson AXE10.
- Media production: Arrangement, announcer, sound mastering and video production.